<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A proclamation appointing the heretors to be in readiness upon fourty eight hours advertisement</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1693-01-12</title>
            <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A92672</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99895761</idno>
  <idno type="VID">153319</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240919891</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1707</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R229992</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99895761</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99895761e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A92672)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 153319)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2359:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A proclamation appointing the heretors to be in readiness upon fourty eight hours advertisement</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1693-01-12</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by the heir of Andrew Anderson, printer to their most excellent Majesties,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1693.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>At end of text: Given under our signet at Edinburgh, the twelfth day of January. and of our reign the fourth year, 1693.</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: Queen ing Premisses.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  History --  1689-1745 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  Politics and government --  1689-1745 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  Scotland</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:153319:1"/>
            <head>A PROCLAMATION, <hi>Appointing the Heretors to be in Readiness upon Fourty Eight Hours Advertisement.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>ILLIAM and MARY by the Grace of God, King and Queen of <hi>Great-Britain, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defenders of the Faith,</signed>
               <salute>to Our Lyon King at Arms, and his Brethren Heraulds, Macers of Our Privy Council, Pursevants, Messengers at Arms, Our Sheriffs in that part, conjunctly and severally, specially constitute, Greet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Forasmuch as, We with Advice of the Lords of Our Privy Council, have thought fit to put the Countrey in a Posture of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence, against any Invasion from Abroad, of <hi>French</hi> and Foreign Papists, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Enemies; Or against any Insurrection at home, from unnatural Countrey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, threatned to this Our antient Kingdom, whereby it may become the Seat of a Bloody War, and for that end, have appointed all the Officers of Our stand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Forces within the said Kingdom, to attend their Duties: And considering that the chief Defence of this Our antient Kingdom, lyes in the Affection and Arms of the Nobility, Gentry, Heretors, Wodsetters, and Liferenters, who owe to Us and their Countrey to be in readiness, and to shew all Alacrity for the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of Religion, Laws and Liberties, and these, and all dear to Us, and Our Subjects, being now at the Stake in the Cases foresaids. Therefore in Order to Our Defence, and the Defence of the Nation, We with Advice foresaid, do Command and Require, all Heretors, Wodsetters, and Liferenters, of whate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver Quality within this Our antient Kingdom, to put themselves presently in readiness with their best Horses, (being good and sufficient) Arms, and Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sions, and that according to their respective Qualities and Estates, to meet and conveen on fourty eight hours Advertisement, and attend Our Host and Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard, as they shall be called by Order from Our Privy Council, for resisting the said Invasion and Insurrection, if the same shall be Attempted, under such Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manders and Officers, as shall be notified to them respectively from Our Council-Table, and at such times, and places as shall be by them appointed, and there to receive such further Orders as shall be given by Us, or these Commissionat by Us; And we do hereby certifie all herein concerned, who shall not attend such Rendezvouzes to be appointed, and obey these Presents in manner above ordained, that they shall be punished as willful Absenters from Our Host and Standard. OUR WILL IS HEREFORE, and we Charge you strictly, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, that incontinent these Our Letters seen, ye pass to the Mercat-crosses of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and remanent Head-burghs of the several Shires within this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and there in Our Name and Authority, make Publication of the Premisses, that none pretend Ignorance; And ordains these Presents to be Printed.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given under Our Signet at</hi> Edinburgh, <date>
                     <hi>the twelfth day of</hi> January. <hi>And of Our Reign the fourth year,</hi> 1693.</date>
               </dateline>
               <hi>Per actum Dominorum Secreti Concilii. In Supplementum Signeti.</hi>
               <signed>DA. MONCREIFF. <hi>Cls. Sti. Concilii.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>
               <hi>God save King</hi> VVilliam <hi>and Queen</hi> Mary.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heir of <hi>Andrew Anderson,</hi> Printer to Their most Excellent Majesties, <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1693.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:153319:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>